You Can't Fight Mother Nature.
Super Eruption is a science fiction, tv movie film directed by Matt Codd.
A Yellowstone National Park scientist and a thrill-seeking ranger join forces to plug-up a
volatile super volcano that threatens to wipe out the entire United States.
Charlie Young, played by Richard Burgi.
Kate, played by Juliet Aubrey.
Claire, played by MyAnna Buring.
George Howe, played by Peter Vollebregt.
Jake, played by Daniel S. Ehrlich.
Josh, played by Alex Wyndham.
A supervolcano is a volcano that has had an eruption with a volcanic
explosivity index (VEI) of 8, the largest recorded value on the index.
This means the volume of deposits for such an eruption is greater
than 1,000 cubic kilometers (240 cubic miles).
Supervolcanoes occur when magma in the mantle rises into
the crust but is unable to break through it.
Pressure builds in a large and growing magma pool until the crust
is unable to contain the pressure and ruptures.
This can occur at hotspots (for example, Yellowstone Caldera)
or at subduction zones (for example, Toba).
Large-volume supervolcanic eruptions are also often associated with large igneous
provinces, which can cover huge areas with lava and volcanic ash.
These can cause long-lasting climate change (such as the triggering of
a small ice age) and threaten species with extinction.
The Oruanui eruption of New Zealand's Taupō Volcano (about 25,600
years ago) was the world's most recent VEI-8 eruption.
The tone is thought_provoking.